#### Daniel O'Neil

135 Innovation Dr.
Bedford, Nova Scotia, B4B 2E7
(902) 471-9917, danieloneil1998@gmail.com
www.danieloneil.ca

# **Profile Summary**

Daniel O'Neil is a graduate of Dalhousie University; he graduated with a Bachelor's of Computer Science May 2021 with a Certificate of Specialization in Cyber Security and Communication Technology. Upon graduation, Mr. O'Neil began working at Jasco Applied Sciences as a Software Engineer and then went on to become a DevSecOps Engineer at Lockheed Martin. At these locations, Mr. O'Neil worked on maritime projects for civilian usage as well as military naval projects for, or in conjunction with, other NATO members. Mr. O'Neil is a quick learner and thrives in both team and solo environments. While working in the software field he has learned to excel in a fast paced work environment, adapt quickly, and developed a deepened appreciation for workplace professionalism.

## **Education and Certifications**

Bachelor of Computer Science, Certificate in Cybersecurity and Communication Technologies, Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS, May 2021

Coursework: Data Structures, Algorithms, Software Engineering, Networks and Network Security, Cloud Computing, Computer Animation, and Mobile Computing

NATO Secret Clearance (Exp. 2031)

HSK II Mandarin Chinese Proficiency

## Links

• GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/DanielONeil1998">https://github.com/DanielONeil1998</a>

• Personal Website: www.danieloneil.ca

# **Skills / Experience Summary**

#### **Technical Skills**

- **Software Development** Workplace experience using the StandUp Agile schema as well as Scrum Methodology to see through the entire software development life cycle;
- **Troubleshooting** Routinely diagnosed and resolved software issues raised by customers and/or QA team members, successfully diagnosed and resolved problems that occurred when deploying containerized flask applications to AWS, and resolved software version discrepancies and data structure inconsistencies while managing segment integration in a collaborative software project;
- **Technical Writing** Authored technical documents to be delivered alongside company products directly to private sector, domestic military, and foreign military recipients;

- Cloud Computing Experience deploying web apps using Amazon Web Services and the utilization of various cloud computing technologies such as load balancers and serverless computation after successfully completing a cloud computing course, receiving A grades on all assignments and projects as well as the private utilization of AWS cloud services to host my personal website as well as video game servers to encourage an always-available collaborative and social gaming environment among my peers;
- Networks and Network Security Advanced knowledge of TCP/IP and network
  infrastructure, understanding of firewalls, encryption, digital signatures, and basic
  knowledge of network security tools and techniques, such as nslookup, Ping, traceroute,
  Nmap, and Wireshark after completion of a network security course receiving an A+
  grade; and
- **Web Development** Completed a web development course as well as a cloud computing course with all web apps created receiving an A grade

#### **Soft Skills**

- Quality Control Worked under a Quality Management System in compliance with ISO 9001:2015 writing technical documentation as well as developing and testing hardware and software:
- **Problem Solving** Strong problem-solving and reasoning skills that contributed to the successful completion of an Undergrad at Dalhousie with a certificate of specialization in Cybersecurity and Communication Technologies and further refined during my time working at Jasco Applied Sciences and Lockheed Martin.
- Public Speaking Organized and ran several meetings at Jasco including test reports, test plan reviews, and work progress reviews as well as giving multiple presentations in both independent and collaborative settings at Dalhousie University and in the Reserves across a wide array of topics, but most commonly either software project presentations or history seminars.
- Leadership Held a volunteer track and field coach position at local schools with responsibilities such as regimen planning, technique instruction, and the supervision of over thirty students at a time as well as managing groups of soldiers during training exercises whilst in the Reserves;
- **Teamwork** Worked in a group setting at Jasco to develop teamwork skills in a highly professional setting as well as collaborated with several groups of students throughout university to plan, develop, and present projects such as developing android apps as well as a set of web apps deployed to the cloud. Was previously employed by the Canadian Armed Forces entailing rigorous team building exercises and practices;
- Customer Service Directly interacted with customers while working at Jasco Applied Sciences receiving product-related feedback, managed client outreach operations to bridge the disconnect between developers and users, and have experience engaging in casual conversation with clients and stakeholders at company barbeque events

#### **Technology Experience**

- Coding Java, Python, Bash, C, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jenkins, Gradle
- **Technologies / Tools -** Microsoft Office, Windows, Linux, PostgreSQL, Git, Amazon Web Services(AWS), REST web services, Docker, Maven

# **Employment History**

## Lockheed Martin,

Aug. 2023 - Present

#### **DevSecOps Engineer**

**Duties:** Developing software products for usage aboard military vessels both domestic and international in nature using build tools such as Jenkins and Gradle, as well as configuring these software products within the vessels themselves.

## **JASCO Applied Sciences**,

Jul. 2021 - Aug. 2023

## **Software Engineer**

**Duties:** Developing and testing software products and writing technical documentation intended for private sector, domestic military, and foreign military consumption in an ISO9001-certified environment.

## **Dalhousie University,**

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2020

#### **Teaching Assistant**

**Duties:** Direct supervision of students performing lab tasks in a software environment, facilitating the face-to-face tutoring of second year computer science students, and providing additional support to students outside of designated office hours.

#### Island Beach Co,

Jul. 2017 - Oct. 2019

#### **Customer Service Sales Representative**

**Duties:** Direct customer services, handling of legal tender, branch financial integrity assurance, resource allocation between nearby branches, on-site technology maintenance/troubleshooting.

#### Canadian Armed Forces, Reserve,

Jul. 2017 - Aug. 2018

#### **Officer in Training**

**Duties:** Organizing extended teamwork-oriented exercises, basic conflict resolution amongst my subordinates, facilitating on-site equipment maintenance and repairs of both mechanical and electronic nature, as well as maintaining the logistical, communicatory, disciplinary, and safety standards in accordance with the Canadian Armed Forces Reserves amongst my assigned subordinates as well as my colleagues.